Let's take a closer look at pairs trade.
我们详细了解下配对交易
When two companies have economic links,
当两家公司经济有关联时
this implies that their stock prices may also move in a similar manner.
表明它们的股价变动也会相似
For example, company A sells frozen green peas,
例如 公司 A 出售冷冻豌豆
and company B cells frozen carrots.
公司 B 出售冷冻胡萝卜
Since frozen peas and carrots are often combined and sold together,
因为冷冻豌豆和胡萝卜经常一起卖
we can see how an increase in sales of peas and carrots would affect both companies.
所以我们可以看出豌豆和胡萝卜销量的增长对两家公司有何影响
Most of the time we see the two stocks moving similarly.
大部分时间 我们发现两支股票的变化相似
However, we may see the two start to diverge.
但是 我们可能看到二者开始分散
When this happens, we use our assumption about their economic ties,
出现这种情况时 我们根据它们的经济关系
and also our assumption about mean-reversion.
以及均值回归规律
We assume that the divergence is temporary and that
假定这种分散是暂时的
the two stock values will revert back to their original long-term relationship.
两支股票的价值将回到原始的长期关系上
The pairs trade involves going long the asset that is priced relatively low.
配对交易会做多价格相对较低的资产
At the same time,
与此同时
the strategy involves going short the asset that is priced relatively high.
做空价格相对较高的资产
If and when the prices start to converge we can close our positions.
当价格开始收敛时 我们就平仓
When I say we close our positions,
平仓是指
I mean that we sell the asset that we originally
卖出一开始买入的资产
buy and we buy the asset that we initially shorted.
并买入一开始做空的资产
Also, if we see the stocks do not converge but continue to diverge over a period of time,
此外 如果我们发现股票没有收敛 而是继续分散
we may also decide to close our positions to cut our losses.
我们也可能会平仓 从而降低损失
You may be wondering how long we should wait before expecting to see the pairs converge.
你可能会疑问 在预计二者收敛时应该等多久？
It helps to look at historical trends.
有必要看看历史走势
Sometimes pairs of socks diverge and then
有时候 一对股票会反复分散和收敛
converge in cycles that may last weeks or months.
并持续几周或几个月
Some traders may decide to trade in shorter time horizons such as in days or even hours.
有些交易者决定在更短的时间内交易 例如几天甚至几小时
For these shorter time periods traders may look for
对于更短的时期 交易者可能会寻找更小的变化
smaller movements to determine what they consider diverging, or converging trends.
并判定他们所认为的分散或收敛走势
There are benefits to trading a pair rather than a single stock.
与交易单个股票相比 配对交易具有一些优势
Trading a pair reduces our exposure to the overall market.
配对交易降低了我们在市场上的敞口
For example, with a single stock,
例如 对于一支股票
we may expect a stock's recent price decline to be temporary.
我们可能认为股票的最近价格下跌是暂时的
However, if a negative jobs report causes most stocks to decline
但是 如果有一篇负面就业报到导致大部分股价下跌
then this overall market movement would carry this single stock downward with it.
那么这种总体市场变化会导致这支股票也跟着下跌
With partnering, we reduce some of the impact of large market movements.
配对交易降低了市场大幅变化的对我们的影响
So, even if both stocks in the pair are pulled down by a general market downturn,
即使一对股票因为市场低迷而下跌
what matters to us is the relative difference between the pair of stocks.
对我们来说重要的是两支股票的相对差异
To describe this relative difference between a pair of
我们将使用价差和对冲比率
stocks we will look into the spread and the hedge ratio.
描述这种相对差异
While the pair of stocks are still converged or linked,
当一对股票依然收敛或关联时
we can imagine holding a long position in stock A and a short position in stock B.
可以想象做多股票 A 并做空股票 B
Our positions are in a certain proportion so that
我们的头寸遵循一定的比例
our combined position has a constant value over time.
使总头寸在一段时间保持常量
In other words, movements in our long position and short position cancel each other out.
也就是说 多头和空头的变化相互抵消
The proportion that lets us create this neutral position is called the hedge ratio.
创建这种中立头寸的比例称为对冲比率
There are two ways to calculate the hedge ratio and they tend to have similar results.
对冲比率有两种计算方式 它们的结果比较相似
One way is to take the price of stock B divided by the price of stock A,
一种方式是用股票 B 的价格除以股票 A 的价格
or the price ratio.
称为价格比率
A second way is to run a linear regression in which stock A is
另一种方式是进行线性回归
the independent variable and stock B is the dependent variable.
其中 A 是自变量 B 是因变量
The coefficient of this regression is our hedge ratio and is similar to the price ratio.
系数 β 是对冲比率 类似于价格比率
The difference is that the regression accounts for a series of
区别在于回归会考虑过去的一系列价格
previous prices while the price ratio uses just the most recent price of each stock.
而价格比率仅考虑最近的价格
Once we have a hedge ratio we can calculate the spread.
得出对冲比率后 我们可以计算价差
The spread is the price of B minus the product of the hedge ratio and price of A.
价差等于 B 的价格减去对冲比率和 A 的价格之积
This may look familiar from our studies of regression.
从回归的角度来说 这个公式看起来比较熟悉
When we used a regression model to estimate the dependent variable we compared
当我们使用回归模型估算因变量时
the prediction with the actual value and called it a residual or error term.
我们将预测值与实际值的差值 称为残差或误差项
Here, we can think of using the hedge ratio to
现在 我们可以使用对冲比率
estimate the price of B using the price of A.
通过 A 的价格估算 B 的价格
We still expect a difference between the estimation and the actual price of B.
我们依然预计 B 的估算价格和实际价格有差异
This difference between the estimation and actual value is called the spread.
估算价格和实际价格之间的差异称为价差